# Shcherbak Aleksei | PHP Developer

#### avatar

Creative PHP (Laravel) Developer with 4+ years of strong experience in backend (PHP, Laravel, C#, .NET) and frontend (vue, jQuery), GOF Design Patterns & OOP areas with willingness to learn new technologies and languages like Golang or Python.

>> PDF version <<

## CONTACTS

- Phone: +7-911-911-4396
- Email: aleksej.shherbak@yandex.ru
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksej-shherbak-538914165/

# **KEY SKILLS**

#### Back End:

- PHP: 5, 7, 8
- C# (as an additional language)

#### Front End:

- · Vue, CSS, HTML
- JavaScript, ES6, REST
- jQuery, Bootstrap

## Databases and storages:

- MySQL
- Postgres
- Redis
- ArangoDb (familiar)

#### Testing:

• PHPUnit, TDD

# DevOps:

• Familiar with Gitlab CI, Jenkins, Github actions, Azure devops

#### Additional instruments and skils:

• Git, Rest, xDebug, Docker / docker-compose, GoF Design Patterns, OOP

### WORK HISTORY

## Quantum Art, Backend Developer, September 2020 - till now

https://quantumart.ru

- Assessing, gathering and validation project requirements using Agile & Scrum principles related to the critical parts of a big telecom operator's website
  resulting in estimation of Level of effort and required working hours.
- Developing new and customization of the existing features (backend 80%, frontend 20%) for the high-volume telecom operator website.
- Documenting implemented features.

### PushApp, Backend Developer, Fullstack Developer, August 2018 — June 2020

https://pushapp.ru

- Maintaining newly developed and legacy systems critical internal web application utilizing PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, JavaScript and ES6, Vue.JS, jQuery.
- Designing new databases and data schemas for the business-critical online service improving data integrity and execution efficiency.
- Creating new web applications from scratch.
- Full Stack development of the high-volume analytical-facing web application applying knowledge of Vue/Vuex and Laravel.
- Performance tunning of the legacy web applications.
- Mentoring and couching newly hired team members.

### Blackidea, Fullstack Developer, December 2017 – June 2018

- Full Stack development of the high-volume eCommerce website using PHP and Bitrix framework.
- Developing web applications from scratch using the company's own architecture PHP boilerplate.

# Seventest, Backend Developer (intern), Backend Developer, February 2015 - June 2015

http://seventest.ru/

• Support legacy web-application using LAMP stack and Drupal 6.

# **PROJECTS**

- https://pushapp.ru (creating own CMS using Laravel)
- https://payforinstall.ru (maintains critical features using Codeigniter)
- https://new.rodovoederevo.ru/ (implementing different backend features and background tasks using .NET Core 3.1 and C#)
- https://mts.ru (Maintaining legacy parts of the website, creating new features according to business demands)
- https://skylink.ru (Support and customization of the existing features)

# **EDUCATION**

• St. Petersburg State University of Telecommunications named after Prof. M.A. Bonch-Bruevich, 2018

# MY STRENGTHS

I do not shift my job to someone else. If I have a problem, and I can't solve it, and it's clear that my colleagues is unlikely to answer me right away, I'd better go to Stackoverflow and ask. In addition to programming, I like music, play guitar in a band. I try to develop comprehensively and not be a "troglodyte", shielded from the whole world by a wall of monitors.

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- English language: B2
- Ready to relocation